Matthew Gwin

mattgwin.udel2024@gmail.com | 443-655-1052 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/mattgwin1/

Summary:

Full Stack software engineer with experience in languages such as C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Kotlin, R, and Arm Assembly. Experienced in Microsoft's .NET framework and Windows application development, as well as website frontend and backend design patterns. Knowledgeable about reverse engineering and well-versed with Apple iOS hardware and software, as well as UNIX operating systems.

Education:

• B.S. Computer Science, Minor Cyber Security, University of Delaware, Expected May 2024

Courses:

 Data Structures, Machine Organization and Assembly Language, Algorithms, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, Database Systems (Oracle), Automata Theory, Parallel Programming, Network Security, Cybersecurity, Compiler Design, Operating Systems, Systems Hardening, Advanced Web Technologies, Web App Security

Skills:

- Programming: Python, Java, C/C++, C#/.NET Framework/Razor, Assembly Language, TypeScript, JavaScript, React, CSS/HTML, SOL, PowerShell, Kotlin, R, Firebase
- Software: iOS, MacOS, Windows, Linux/UNIX, Oracle, Git, Perforce, Microsoft Office Suite, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins, Google Cloud

Professional Experience:

Software Engineering Intern, Hologic Inc, 5/2022 - 8/2022, 1/2023 - 2/2023, 5/2023 - 8/2023:

- Work in a team with other software engineer interns to develop an internal tool to aid checking developer productivity and assist with release notes
- Use C# and Windows Presentation Framework to write an application from scratch
- Learn MVC and MVVM programming interaction between frontend UI and backend code
- Script in PowerShell to copy log files off of testing machines
- Develop an internal website using C# Razor to kickoff automated builds and overnight software installations on testing computers
- Develop an understanding of Agile Methodology, working to meet deadlines and observing sprints

LBSCI, Lovola Blakefield, 03/2019 - 06/2019, 10/2019 - 03/2020:

• Taught a class on fundamentals of low-level iOS operating system components

IT Intern, Loyola Blakefield, 06/2017 - 8/2017, 6/2018 - 8/2018, 6/2019 - 8/2019:

- Deployed software to students
- Trained students on laptop usage guidelines
- Resolved student software issues